I'll just take a quick moment to introduce myself to convince you that I am actually qualified to be
잠깐 제 소개를 할게요 8주간의 여정을 함께할 자격이 있다는
taking you on this eight week journey.
걸 증명하려고요
So my name is Ed Donner.
전 에드 도너예요
I've got about 20 years of experience in software engineering, data science, and tech leadership.
소프트웨어 공학 데이터 과학 기술 리더십 분야에서 20년 경력을 쌓았어요
Most of my career at JP Morgan, where at the end I ran engineering teams of about 300 people.
JP 모건에서 근무하며 300명 정도 되는 엔지니어링 팀을 운영했어요
I started out in London where I'm from.
제 고향인 런던에서 시작했어요
I then moved to Tokyo for a bit and ended up in New York City, where I live now.
그 후 도쿄로 잠시 이사했고 지금은 뉴욕에 살고 있죠 비트 코스트
After JP Morgan, I founded a couple of AI startups.
JP 모건 이후 인공지능 스타트업 두 개를 설립했죠
My first startup was sold, was acquired a couple of years ago, and in fact, that picture on the bottom
제 첫 스타트업 회사가 몇 년 전에 팔렸어요 오른쪽 하단의
right shows the moment when it was announced on a Times Square billboard.
사진을 보시면 타임스스퀘어 광고판에 발표됐을 때예요
That was a particularly magical moment for me.
제게는 특히 마법 같은 순간이었어요
But I don't want to show you that photo to brag about my Times Square moment, but also because, curiously,
타임스스퀘어에서의 추억을 자랑하려고 사진을 보여드리긴 싫지만 신기하게도 타임스스퀘어
I actually live very near Times Square.
근처에 살거든요
It's an unusual place to live because it's such a sort of tourist place to be.
독특한 곳이에요 관광지로 유명하기 때문이죠
But if you see these two red arrows and you imagine where they join up, that's basically where I live.
빨간 화살표 두 개가 만나는 곳을 상상해 보세요 제가 사는 곳이에요
And that's where I am right now.
지금 제가 그래요
And so if you can imagine if I wave at you right now, if this were somehow a real time photo, you'd
제가 지금 여러분께 손을 흔든다고 상상해 보세요 이게 실시간 사진이라면 저
have a little me waving at you from roundabout where those red lines meet.
빨간 선이 만나는 곳에서 제가 여러분께 손을 흔들고 있을 거예요
Okay.
네
And the final thing to mention, the picture in the middle at the bottom shows me flying.
마지막으로 말씀드릴 건 가운데 하단 사진에 제가 나는 게 나와요
Or in front of a plane.
비행기 앞일 수도 있죠
You might be thinking, that's me saying, this is my big passion, my hobby, I fly planes.
비행기 조종이 취미라고 생각하는 분도 계시겠죠
But in fact, that's that's not not what I was going to say.
하지만 사실 제가 하려던 말은 그게 아니에요
It turns out that whilst I'm very proficient and highly skilled in the field of llms, that does not
저는 llms에 능숙하고 숙련된 조종사지만 눈과 손의 협응력은 전혀
translate in any way to my hand-eye coordination, which is terrible on almost any front, including
발휘하지 못했어요 거의 모든 전선에서 형편없었죠 비행기를 조종할 때도
flying planes where I have tried and am very shaky to say the least.
해 봤지만 솔직히 말하면 너무 불안했어요
So if it turns out that you find yourself in a plane and you look at the cockpit and you see that I
여러분이 비행기 안에 있다고 가정해 보죠 조종석에 앉은 사람이 저라고
am the person there on the stick, I suggest you look quickly for the nearest parachute.
생각한다면 재빨리 가까운 낙하산을 찾으세요
But if it comes to you needing to go on an eight week course to build up commercial expertise in how
하지만 8주 과정을 거쳐 상업적 전문성을 쌓아야만 달 착륙선 엔지니어가
to be an LM engineer, then you've come to the right place.
될 수 있다면 잘 찾아오셨어요
All right, without further ado, let's get to the course.
자, 그럼 본격적으로 시작할게요 get it